Guide to the Stanford University, ACME Project, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, ACME Project, records
1961-1973
SC0236
Lederberg, Joshua
6 Linear feet
Collection consists of files relating to the ACME (Advanced Computer Medical Experiments) Project at Stanford, use of computers, and the establishment of a computer center at Stanford. Included are correspondence (including some by Gio Wiederhold), committee records, budget materials, grant files, and publications.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Transferred by Professor Joshua Lederberg, 1979.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of Genetics at Stanford Medical School (1959-1978). Lederberg received a Nobel prize in 1958 and became president of Rockefeller Univeristy in 1978.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of files relating to the ACME (Advanced Computer Medical Experiments) Project at Stanford, use of computers, and the establishment of a computer center at Stanford. Included are correspondence (including some by Gio Wiederhold), committee records, budget materials, grant files, and publications.
Access Terms
Lederberg, Joshua; Stanford University. Advanced Computer Medical Experiments project.; Stanford University. Computation Center.; Wiederhold, Gio.; Medicine--Data processing.
Collection Contents
- Original Accession
  - Computing Newsletters, July 20, 1971 - August 10, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Medical Computing 1961-64 (Before ACME) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACME Budget, September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ACME, IBM 270X Equipment Contract (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ACME Correspondence: Gio Wiederhold, Dec. 1965- Sep. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ACME - NIH Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proposal to IBM, 10/1/1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ACME - IBM Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACME Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ACME Site Visit, 4/16/69 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Recommendations re: Data Processing at Stanford Hospital (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clinical Computer Applications Committee (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ACME Policy Meeting 10/31/69 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ACME Committee (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ACME Policy Committee Meeting 12/5/69 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ACME General (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ACME Administration, Facilities, etc. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ACME Funding, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - RR-00311-06: ACME, 1971-72 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ACME Proposal (File copies) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - SIGMA 5 Computer Proposal (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ACME Bids (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Macy Grant (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ACME Macy Foundation Grant, 1/1/66 - 12/31/66 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ACME Notes H120CH - HRUST (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACME Notes HSC - I53 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - ACME Notes KA - TDUONB (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ACME Notes TEP - UW (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ACME Notes VP - ZXL (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Budget Statements: NIH Grant (0-KKG-041), August 1969 - September 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Budget Statements: Clearing Account (0-KKG-073), August 1969 - September 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Budget Statements: Clearing Account (0-KKF-073), September 1972 - August 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Budget Statements: User Services (0-KKG-045), September 1972 - August 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Budget Statements: Systems Programmers (0-KKF-043), September 1972 - August 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Budget Statements: Director's Office (0-KKG-042), September 1972 - August 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Budget Statements: Operations (0-KKG-044), September 1972 - August 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - ACME Notes EAA - GPROB (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ACME Notes HAD - I (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ACME Book for Site Visitors (NIH), April 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - NIH Correspondence, Year 01, 9/66 - 7/67 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ACME: NIH Application FR 00311-01 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - ACME: NIH Application FR 00311-02 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ACME: NIH Application FR 00311-03 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - NIH Correspondence, Year 02, 8/67 - 7/68 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - NIH Correspondence, Year 03, 8/68 - 7/69 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Annual Report, Year 03, 8/68 - 7/69 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - NIH Correspondence, Year 04, 8/69 - 7/70 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ACME: NIH RR 00311-04 Renewal, 1969-72 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Audit on ACME, June 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - NIH Correspondence, Year 05, 8/70 - 7/71 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - ACME: NIH RR 00311-05 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - FR 00311-04 Report (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report, Year 05, 8/70 - 7/71 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report, Year 05, 8/70 - 7/71 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Annual Report, Year 06, 8/71 - 7/72 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - NIH Correspondence, Year 06SI, 8/72 - 7/73 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - NIH Correspondence, Year 06, 8/71 - 7/72 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - NIH RR 00311-06SI, 8/1/72 - 7/31/73 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Annual Report, Year 06SI, 8/72 - 7/73 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - NIH Site Visit, April 16, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Presentation Data for ACME (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - ACME Final and Index to Notes (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Metanote by Lederberg (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - ACME Notes AA - BUL (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ACME Notes CAB - EDZ (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Letterbook (ACME staff), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Letterbook (R. Jamtgaard), July - Dec. 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chronological Letterbook (R. Jamtgaard), Jan. - June 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chronological Letterbook (R. Jamtgaard), Jan. - Dec. 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chronological Letterbook (R. Jamtgaard), July - Dec. 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chronological Letterbook (R. Jamtgaard), Jan. - June 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chronological Letterbook (Real-Time Staff), Jan-Dec. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chronological Letterbook (Real-Time Staff), May-Dec. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-102
  - ACME Notes: AA – ADISK (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ACME Notes: ADJ – AO (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACME Notes: AP - ATSC (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ACME Notes: ATYNET - BV (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ACME Notes: CAB - DELL (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ACME Notes: DG - EAO (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ACME Notes: EB - EBZ (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ACME Notes: ECABLE - EDZ (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACME Notes: EEA - EIBMTP (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ACME Notes: EIRP - FC (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ACME Notes: FD - FPKR (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACME Notes: FR - GPROB (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ACME Notes: H120CH - HCIC (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ACME Notes: HCL - HDR (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ACME Notes: HF - HK (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ACME Notes: HL - HPWR (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ACME Notes: HQ - HTRI (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ACME Notes: HUA - HXU (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ACME Notes: HY – KW (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ACME Notes: LIDAN - NT (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ACME Notes: OA - PK (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ACME Notes: PL - SYM (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ACME Notes: T - TEP (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ACME Notes: TER - TODD (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ACME Notes: TODP – TR (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - ACME Notes: TS – VR (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ACME Notes: WAA - WKT (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACME Notes: WMON - XPL (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - ACME Notes: YAA - YMU (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ACME Notes: YNP - ZYL (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ACME User Notes 1968-70 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ACME Newsletter / Computing Newsletter 1970-73 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ACME Conversion Notes 1974-75 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Medical Computing Services Bulletin, 1973-74 (Box 2, Folder 8)